<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>

		<!-- Adaptation -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGEGROUP_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_GROUP_NAME"><Text>Adaptation</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_ADAPT_TITLE"><Text>Adaptation</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_ADAPT_PARA_1"><Text>When you settle your original capital, the game checks the surrounding terrain within a 2-tile radius. If it detects a high number of tundra, desert, or mountain tiles, it gives your empire a special bonus to help cope with that type of environment. This bonus is permanent - it lasts until the end of the game, and applies to all of your cities.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_ADAPT_PARA_2"><Text>There are a few things to keep in mind:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]It does not matter whether the surrounding tiles are owned by you or not.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Only your capital can give you an adaptation bonus. Subsequent settled cities do not.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]It is possible (though extremely rare) to get two adaptations at once.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Tundra Mountains and Desert Mountains count towards the mountain adaptation, NOT the tundra or desert adaptations.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Some civilizations have special exceptions where they will only get part of an adaptation bonus, or none at all. Those are listed below next to each possible adaptation.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_TUNDRA_TITLE"><Text>Tundra adaptation</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_TUNDRA_PARA_1"><Text>If there are 7 or more Tundra/Tundra Hills or Snow/Snow Hills tiles within 2 tiles of your capital when it's founded, your civilization will adapt to life in the tundra.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_TUNDRA_PARA_2"><Text>Getting this adaptation grants your Builders the ability to build Farms on flat Tundra tiles straight away, as well as on Tundra Hills at Civil Engineering. And any Farms that you do build on tundra will get +1 [ICON_Production] Production.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_TUNDRA_PARA_3"><Text>Exceptions:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Russia will not get extra [ICON_Production] Production on its tundra Farms.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Canada will not get any bonus from this adaptation.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_DESERT_TITLE"><Text>Desert adaptation</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_DESERT_PARA_1"><Text>If there are 7 or more Desert/Desert Hills tiles within 2 tiles of your capital when it's founded, your civilization will adapt to life in the desert.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_DESERT_PARA_2"><Text>Getting this adaptation grants your Builders the ability to build Farms on flat Desert tiles straight away, as well as on Desert Hills at Civil Engineering. And any Farms that you do build on desert will get +1 [ICON_Production] Production and [ICON_Faith] Faith.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_DESERT_PARA_3"><Text>Exceptions:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Mali will not get extra [ICON_Faith] Faith on its desert Farms.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_MOUNTAINS_TITLE"><Text>Mountain adaptation</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_MOUNTAINS_PARA_1"><Text>If there are 5 or more Mountain tiles within 2 tiles of your capital when it's founded, your civilization will adapt to life in the mountains.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_MOUNTAINS_PARA_2"><Text>Getting this adaptation grants your [ICON_Citizen] Citizens the ability to work mountain tiles, with a base yield of 1 [ICON_Production] Production and 1 [ICON_Faith] Faith. In addition to this, your mountains will gain +1 [ICON_Food] Food per adjacent Farm.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_EPSMOD_ADAPTATION_CHAPTER_EPSMOD_MOUNTAINS_PARA_3"><Text>Exceptions:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Inca's mountains will not gain extra [ICON_Production] Production, but they will gain +1 [ICON_Faith] Faith, and the extra [ICON_Food] Food from regular Farms in addition to Terrace Farms.</Text></Row>

		<!-- Civic units -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_LANDSKNECHT_PIKEMAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>Brainchild of archduke Maximilian I von Habsburg, the landsknecht were German mercenary pikemen of the 16th century. They were created in imitation of the legendary Swiss Reisläufer after their decisive victories in the Burgundian Wars, and would eventually supplant them as the best mercenary infantry available in Europe, fighting in almost every major engagement in the 16th century – often on both sides.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_LANDSKNECHT_PIKEMAN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>In battle, landsknechts generally carried pikes of up to twenty feet in length. Some few also carried huge two-handed swords or halberds; these were used to chop the heads off of the pikes of their opponents. As the 16th century progressed and European armies steadily embraced gunpowder, landsknechts saw increased use in Pike and Shot formations.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_LANDSKNECHT_PIKENSHOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>Brainchild of archduke Maximilian I von Habsburg, the landsknecht were German mercenary pikemen of the 16th century. They were created in imitation of the legendary Swiss Reisläufer after their decisive victories in the Burgundian Wars, and would eventually supplant them as the best mercenary infantry available in Europe, fighting in almost every major engagement in the 16th century – often on both sides.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_LANDSKNECHT_PIKENSHOT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>In battle, landsknechts generally carried pikes of up to twenty feet in length. Some few also carried huge two-handed swords or halberds; these were used to chop the heads off of the pikes of their opponents. As the 16th century progressed and European armies steadily embraced gunpowder, landsknechts saw increased use in Pike and Shot formations.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_TEMPLAR_KNIGHT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>After the conquest of Jerusalem by the first christian crusade in the late 11th century, its leaders were burdened with many new administrative and humanitarian problems in a very unstable political situation. Several of the crusading knights stepped up to the task of solving them as volunteers, forming religious orders in the style of monastic ones, each devoted to a specific purpose in the holy land, such as the Knights Templar, the Knights Hospitaller, and the Teutonic Knights. After these initial organisations were recognized by the Pope and gained fame across Christianity, several other orders were formed across Europe to combat what the Vatican perceived as threats to it: Muslim invaders in the Iberian Peninsula (modern-day Spain and Portugal) and Eastern Europe, as well as pagan tribes.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_TEMPLAR_KNIGHT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>Of these, by far the most famous were the Templars. Their order was formed in 1119 as the "Poor Fellow-Soldiers of Christ and of the Temple of Solomon", and was dedicated to the protection of christian pilgrimages to the holy land. While the city of Jerusalem was secure, the surrounding lands were plagued by bandits and marauders preying upon the defenseless pilgrims. The Templars guarded them as armed escorts, but also provided an innovative financial service that let the pilgrims deposit their wealth for safekeeping, making them less desirable targets for the bandits.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_TEMPLAR_KNIGHT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>The order started out consisting of only 9 knights, but through popularity and plentiful donations grew exponentially to one of the most influential forces in the medieval world. Pope Innocent II granted them exemption from obeying local laws, meaning they could cross any borders, did not need to pay taxes, or answer to anyone other than the Pope. They used this priviliged status to build an expansive network of commanderies, forts, farms, and industries across Europe, and served as its de facto banking system. However, after Jerusalem was lost, support for the order waned, and was replaced with a growing mistrust. They reached a size where they started being inconvenient for many nobles, and wild rumors swirled about their secret rites and traditions. King Philip IV of France used this as an opportunity to get rid of the massive debt he accrued with the order, by getting rid of the order itself. He pressured the Pope into disbanding it in 1312 without warning, arrested its members in France, tortured them into giving false confessions of herecy, and burned them at the stake.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_TEMPLAR_KNIGHT_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4"><Text>The combined astronomical wealth, secrecy, and dramatic end of the Templars gave rise to much speculation and conspiracy theories in the centuries that followed, keeping their name in various writings long past when the other orders lost all relevance. Because of this, a rich mythos surrounding their legends endures in pop culture, and the original meaning of the term "Templar" eroded. It has instead come to be used as a blanket term for any knight belonging to a religious order.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_COMMANDO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>In June of 1940, after the disastrous setbacks in the Battle of France, Winston Churchill called for the formation of a special force trained to carry out hit-and-run raids into German-occupied Europe. Lieutenant Colonel Dudley Clarke, assistant to the Chief of the Imperial General Staff tasked with carrying out this directive, suggested that the new regiment be modelled after the Boer commandos, and the tactics they employed in the Second Boer War of 1899-1902. The resulting force would come to be known as the British Commandos, who served in every major theatre of World War II, and greatly influenced the formation of other special forces in virtually every allied country thereafter.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_COMMANDO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The word "commando" saw its first use in the mid-17th century, in the Dutch Cape Colony in south Africa, where it referred to a band of mounted militia. The language of origin, however, is disputed. Various sources cite it as either Dutch ("kommando") or Portuguese ("comando"), or even Afrikaans, which in turn borrowed the word from one of the other two and gave it the meaning of "militia" or "raid". After breaking off from the Dutch colonials, the Boers continued using commando units in unconventional tactics to stave off the numerically superior Zulu, and later against the British Imperial army in the Boer Wars.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_CIVIC_UNIT_COMMANDO_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>The British Commandos used a mixture of small-group raids by boat or paradrop as well as rapid assaults by entire brigades in various operations across the war. They were less heavily armed and armored than their regular infantry counterparts, and used an assortment of specialised gear that gave them increased mobility, as well as some ability to carry out raids silently. This unconventional loadout and approach carried over into most subsequent special forces modelled after them, though in modern times those tend to focus more on direct assualt, frontline reconnaissance, and counterinsurgency.</Text></Row>

		<!-- Support units -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_SHIELDBEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>Up until the invention of gunpowder, all armed conflict mankind engaged in was fought using melee, some variation of arrows, or both. This meant that any new military advancements in the Classical and Medieval periods were in the form of new formations or heavier implements of wood and steel, both of which would reduce soldiers' ability to move around and react to things quickly. The more specialised a unit was, the more vulnerable it would be to more nimble combatants. To solve this issue, various armies across this period would dedicate detachments of more lightly-armed troops to guarding the larger unit against flanking and enemy archers. These would often carry large shields into battle, and would thus be referred to as "Shield bearers".</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_SHIELDBEARER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The earliest known instance of shieldbearers were the Macedonian Hypaspists, who carried Aspis shields to guard the flanks of sarissa-wielding phalanxes in Philip's army. Other notable examples include the Persian Sparabara, which used large rectangular wicker shields in a shield-wall formation to protect more vulnerable troops, as well as Italian Pavisiers that carried ornate pavise shields for archers and crossbowmen to take cover behind while they loaded their next shot. Shieldbearers have also been known to protect wielders of early handguns in the Hussite Wars, as well as escort high-ranking officers as bodyguards.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_SNIPER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>Snipers are marksmen trained in the use of high-precision rifles for various support tasks alongside regular infantry. Their first instance is traced back to the sharpshooters on both sides of the American Revolutionary war, who used the first available firearms with rifling to great effect against the other combatants armed with much less acurate muskets.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_SNIPER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The term itself comes from British India in the late 18th century, where hunting was a common pastime for imperial officers, and one of the hardest local things to hunt was a bird species called a snipe. The act of hunting it was colloquially referred to as "sniping", and thus a person skilled in it would be called a "sniper." The British imperial army continued using sharpshooters for many conflicts in the 19th century, but it was in the Second Boer War that their first dedicated sniper unit, the Lovat Scouts, was formed.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_SNIPER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>By the time World War I rolled around, all sides of the conflict employed snipers, which proved particularly powerful in the western trenches, prompting lots of resources to be poured into training more at specialised sniper schools. These were mostly disbanded in the interbellum, until World War II brought them back into ubiquity, especially on the Soviet side who trained almost half a million of them.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_SNIPER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4"><Text>Contrary to pop culture, most snipers do not operate solo - they are paired into a team with a spotter, and often a flanker as well. The sniper operates the high-precision rifle (that is often too hefty to carry alone) to either pick off key targets, suppress enemies while a friendly infantry unit is on the move, or simply to surveil the terain and find targets for artillery and air strikes. The spotter assists in the surveillance and target acquisition, calculating firing trajectory factors, and communicating with the rest of the unit. The flanker is usually armed with an automatic weapon, and guards against surprise attacks from the flanks and the rear, where the sniper has a blindspot. In urban combat, it is common for two or more sniper teams to be deployed in tandem for better coverage.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_DEMOLITION_CREW_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The use of self-contained explosive devices that we call "bombs" in warfare is almost as old as the use of gunpowder itself. The Song Dynasty in China used bombs made out of bamboo tubes as early as the 11th century. The classic cast-iron black spherical bombs were also a Chinese invention. They were called "thunder-crash bombs" for the loud thundering noise they created, and were used by both by the Jin and Song dynasties in the 13th century. The invading Mongols adopted the design and used it in their subsequent invasion of Japan, as well as incursions into the rest of Asia and Europe. Which is why they are often credited with spreading the technology of gunpowder to the rest of the world, alongside the Ottoman Empire.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_DEMOLITION_CREW_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>As science progressed and the design of explosives advanced, armies saw an increased need in explosives experts on the field, to prevent the destructive ordinances from blowing up their own ranks due to misuse. This need accelerated as advances in chemistry in the 19th century introduced new types of explosive substances to the military: nitroglycerin, TNT, dynamite, and C-4. All of which had special considerations for their safe use.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_MODERN_DEMO_CREW_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The use of self-contained explosive devices that we call "bombs" in warfare is almost as old as the use of gunpowder itself. The Song Dynasty in China used bombs made out of bamboo tubes as early as the 11th century. The classic cast-iron black spherical bombs were also a Chinese invention. They were called "thunder-crash bombs" for the loud thundering noise they created, and were used by both by the Jin and Song dynasties in the 13th century. The invading Mongols adopted the design and used it in their subsequent invasion of Japan, as well as incursions into the rest of Asia and Europe. Which is why they are often credited with spreading the technology of gunpowder to the rest of the world, alongside the Ottoman Empire.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_MODERN_DEMO_CREW_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>As science progressed and the design of explosives advanced, armies saw an increased need in explosives experts on the field, to prevent the destructive ordinances from blowing up their own ranks due to misuse. This need accelerated as advances in chemistry in the 19th century introduced new types of explosive substances to the military: nitroglycerin, TNT, dynamite, and C-4. All of which had special considerations for their safe use.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_EPSMOD_SUPPORT_UNIT_PATHFINDER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The use of mercenaries - individuals that get involved in wars for personal profit rather than any kind of allegiance or ideological motivation - dates back further than recorded history can even account for. The earliest known record of them saw the Ancient Greeks hiring fighters from other city-states in the 6th century BC. Most mercenaries engage in combat directly, but there are other ways to profit from a passing army. The practice of hiring locals as guides through unfamiliar or dangerous terrain regularly appears in a multitude of records across history, especially during colonial conquests. In the right geographical location, a skilled pathfinder can earn a sizeable wealth from a raging conflict.</Text></Row>

		<!-- Tall buildings -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_COLLEGE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The word "college" comes from latin and is a combination of the words "co-" for "together" and "lego" for "gather, collect, pick", thus translating as "a group selected together for a purpose". In its original form, "collegium" was used in ancient Rome to refer to social and trade groups that operated under a single legal personality, akin to modern corporations. Much of the modern western multi-tiered education system is modelled after the one used in the Roman empire; however, it is unclear if the Romans themselves ever used the word "college" to describe any part of it. Most of the oldest known instances of educational colleges date back to the medieval ages, such as Eton College that was founded by King Henry VI in 1440, as well as the Islamic Madrasah.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_COLLEGE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>In modern parlance, a college can mean any number of different tiers of educational body, from secondary schools, through  vocational colleges that provide specific technical skills, all the way to being used as a synonym to universities, or constituent parts of universities. The exact nomenclature and meaning varies by country, as does the tuition structure and the curriculum.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_INSTITUTE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The characteristic that defines institutes and differentiates them from universities and colleges is that they are founded by a government with the express purpose of conducting research into a specific field. Though in practice, institutes often operate as educational or vocational bodies as well, and the word can also be used to describe professional ones. It originates from the latin "institutum" ("facility", "habit"), which is derived from "instituere" ("build", "create", "raise", "educate").</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_INSTITUTE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The earliest known reseach institutes were almost all observatories dedicated to the study of astronomy (and by extension, mathematics), established in the medieval and renaissance periods across the Islamic world, India, and Europe. The enlightenment period of the 17-18th centuries saw European monarchs establish some of the most famous ones: the Royal Society of Britan, the Académie royale des sciences in France, and the St Petersburg Academy in Russia. In modern times, space agencies such as NASA and ESA as well as subatomic particle research centers in the vein of CERN and ESRF are all examples of institutes.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_CULTURE_MINISTRY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The word "minister" comes from the latin "minus" ("minor, less"), and translates as a "servant", "assistant", or "subordinate". Thus the verb form "to minister" means to "serve as a subordinate to someone", and the usual connotation for the title of minister is to serve as subordinate to a ruler or government, as the head of a department dedicated to specific role, called a ministry.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_CULTURE_MINISTRY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The earliest uses of the word date back to the 14th century within the Christian Church, to refer to the act of providing religious rites and services to people. And one of the big services the Church was responsible for at the time was the organizing of fairs - big yearly market and entertainment events revolving around the celebration of a particular saint's day. However, as time moved on, monarchs had to start getting more and more involved as the raucous and messy nature of the fairs would often result in outbursts of violence, and riots. As such, fairs would eventually only be held by a royal charter, in locations where order could be maintained by a bishop, sherrif, or governor, presiding in a small court of justice on the fairground, called a pye powder court.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_CULTURE_MINISTRY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>This rudimentary structure was one of first instances of what we would now call a Ministry of Culture - a government-appointed committee responsible for the organization of big cultural events involving large masses of people, in an orderly fashion.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_BROADCAST_STATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The early history of radio in the 1910s was marked by a haphazard approach, wherein rival manufacturers created the first stations to provide content for customers of their hardware, with little to no oversight or coordination. This free-for-all proved problematic for the military and civil sectors, who wanted to use radio for purposes deemed way more impotant than commercial, but were impeded by signal interference from the burgeoning broadcast industry. To reign in the madness, governments started regulating radio in the 1920s, mandating the purchase of a license, and restricting which frequencies a station could use.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_BROADCAST_STATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>Some nations, however, went a step further. Eager to avoid the chaotic expansion it saw in the Unitade States, Britain's GPO established a single broadcast authority in the UK owned by a consortium of manufacturers in 1922 - the British Broadcasting Company. Within a few short years this organization was re-structured into the first national broadcast station in the world - the British Broadcasting Corporation. It operated under a crown charter, and served as the UK's sole source of programming for the subsequent 3 decades.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_BROADCAST_STATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>Other nations in Europe and parts of the world also took a similar trajectory, first centralising all radio broadcasting under a national entity in the early 20th century, then allowing commercial competition in its latter half. This meant that for a sizeable part of modern history, people in these countries had no choice but to all experience the same shows, leaving a deep impact on how their culture would shape.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_GRAND_TEMPLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>A Grand Temple is a revered holy site held sacred among the followers of a given religion, and usually considered its capital. These temples often feature grand architecture and ornate inscriptions that stand for centuries as a testament to the faith of the religion's adherents. Famous examples include St. Peter's Basilica in the Vatican, the lost Temple of Solomon in Jerusalem, the Great Mosque of Mecca, and the Grand Temple of Mount Heng.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_GRAND_TEMPLE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>Although there is no clear consensus as to which of the many temples found throughout the world today is the oldest, many believe the Göbekli Tepe - found in modern Turkey and assembled over 12,000 years ago - to be the earliest man-made religious structure ever discovered.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_THEOLOGICAL_COLLEGE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>As far as the bigger picture of human civilization is concerned, the separation of education from religion is a very recent concept. For much of recorded history, institutions of higher education were either run by religions directly, or were closely tied to them. Most of the oldest universities were founded with the primary goal of teaching Theology, with other subjects added in to support it, rather than working toward a secular pursuit.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_THEOLOGICAL_COLLEGE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>That only started to change with the onset of the European Enlightenment in the 17th century, when physicists and philosophers started forming scientific theory, and questioning the place of a discipline that demanded reverence of a specific religion's dogma in institutions devoted to independent thought. Eventually, this would lead to a split between secular bodies of education founded by governments, and religious education founded by the Church. Though much of the tiered structure and naming conventions would remain the same.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_ROYAL_TREASURY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>For as long as rare items have existed and civilized society placed special value into them, there existed a need to safely store them for safekeeping, in dedicated rooms or entire buildings called treasuries. In the earliest known accounts from Classical times, treasuries were almost always a part of a temple, used to store offerings to the gods and religious artifacts. By the time of the Roman Empire they were starting to serve a secular function - both the Senate and the emperor each had their own treasury, called the aerarium and fiscus, respectively.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_ROYAL_TREASURY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The prevalence of royal treasuries, used by monarchs for taxation and finance, ramped up significantly in the medieval era, as evidenced by the massive structures built to house them - castles. In addition to serving as strongholds for the military, castles would often have a secure room for storing treasure deep within them, either temporarily, or in the case of castles housing the monarch themselves - permanently. These centralised places of wealth would serve as the core of a kingdom's financials, and strategic points of feudal conflict.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_ROYAL_TREASURY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>In modern times, with the prevalence of paper money and digital transactions, physical treasuries are generally only used as a place to keep a country's gold reserves, whereas the term "treasury" is used to describe the government's financial department instead.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_BANK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>The pieces of paper money that we commonly use today (when we're not doing digital payments) are what is known as "banknotes." In their original form invented by the Chinese in the 7th century, they were not currency in and of themselves, but rather a promissary note issued by an institution, with the guarantee that when you brought that note back to it, it would give you the amount of actual legal tender written on them. Which was usually rare-metal coins.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_BANK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The concept spread to Europe in the middle ages, and would serve as the foundational core of the earliest banks thereafter. The system worked so well that merchants and rulers eventually stopped carrying around coins altogether, and got in the habbit of using bank-issued notes as a de facto currency. So a transition into making them actual legal tender only seemed like the logical next step. In practice though, that proved problematic. All banks that operated at the time were privately-owned commercial enterprises, each with their own unique banknote. Each region within a single country would be served by its own bank, meaning the further away from the capital you traveled, the more different notes you needed to deal with. Especially when crossing borders in international payments.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_NATIONAL_BANK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>In order for paper money to become an effective currency, all banks operating under a single government needed to be forced to use the same banknotes. The first stab at this idea came from the Dutch Wisselbank in 1609, but the first true central bank is considered to be the Bank of England, which through the Tonnage Act of 1694 gained an exclusive monopoly on issuing Britain's banknotes, as well as possession of the government's balances. Both of these would serve as the model for what we now call a "national" or "central" bank - a special institution that manages the monetary policy of the state, and oversees other commercial banks operating within it.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_RETINUE_QUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1"><Text>In the centuries where populations were ruled by princes and monarchs, it was a common practice for lords in power to gather a special contingent of people around them, to stand ready to perform specialized tasks when they were needed. In the middle ages, this group of people would be called that lord's "affinity" or "retinue", and it would include military servants (f.e. knights) as well as non-military personel, such as indentured retainers and free tradesmen.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_RETINUE_QUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2"><Text>The civilian part of a retinue would either be formally obligated to only offer their services exclusively to the lord (retainers), or simply kept as a contact in a mutually beneficial arrangement (non-retainers). Both would be given a special mark of office from the lord, called a "livery", as well as privileged protection from judicial proceedings called "maintenance." They would usually be recruited from the local gentry, but it was also common for medieval rulers to invite big groups of foreign nationals to live in their lands, as a way to get access to their rarified skills. This would often result in a surge of a population and rapid development for a city, as well as make it a melting pot of different cultures.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_EPSMOD_TALL_BUILDING_RETINUE_QUARTERS_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3"><Text>In modern times, the only profession that refers to themsleves as "retainers" anymore is legal council. Attorneys will often sign a retainer agreement with their clients, which outlines the payment structure and terms of their services before any actual litigation occurs. Unlike with the retainers of medieval times, though, the contract usually does not bind the attorney to only provide their services to that one client.</Text></Row>
		
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>